Guide to the John T. Yates, Jr. Papers, 1960-2015 UA.90.F106
ULS Archives & Special Collections
John T. Yates, Jr. Papers
1960-2015
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Yates, John T., Jr.
UA.90.F106
11.25 Linear Feet (9 boxes)
Biography
John T. Yates, Jr., an American chemist, physicist, and astronomer, was born in 1935 in Winchester, Virginia, and died in 2015 in Free Union, Virginia. Yates attended Juniata College, where he received a Bachelor's degree in Chemistry in 1956, and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, where he received his Ph.D. in Physical Chemistry in 1960. After graduation, Yates served as an Assistant Professor at Antioch College in Ohio from 1960 to 1963. Yates then proceeded to work at the National Bureau of Standards in Washington, D.C from 1965 to 1981. During his time at the NBS, he was a visiting professor at the University of East Anglia and California Institute of Technology.
In 1982, Yates settled at the University of Pittsburgh, where he served as the first R.K. Mellon Professor of Chemistry from 1982 to 2006. While at Pitt, Yates was the Founding Director of the Surface Science Center, his specialized field. In 1994, he was given appointment to the Physics and Astronomy departments. Yates was the lead researcher in creating a coating that detected biochemical dangers in the air for the Defense Advanced Research Project Agency in 2001. In 2004, Yates was a head researcher in studies on carbon nanotubes, dubbed the World's Smallest Test Tubes. In 2006, he aided in the creation of semi-conductor islands smaller than 10 nanometers called Quantum Dots, which was an integral step toward the creation of Quantum computers. After retiring from Pitt in 2007, Yates joined the University of Virginia as a Shannon Research Fellow and Professor. During this time, Yates found himself involved in astrochemistry. Yates was the winner of various awards both locally and internationally. He was also a member of numerous scientific organizations, notably the National Academy of Sciences.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection covers the research, publications, patent, teaching, and professional activities of John T. Yates, Jr., as well as his awards and honors. The collection provides an overview of Yates' carreer at the National Bureau of Standards, the University of Pittsburgh, and the University of Virginia. Each series spans the wide variety of interests that Yates had throughout his career.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Karen Yates in August 2016 and 2021.
Surface chemistry; University of Pittsburgh; Faculty papers; Chemistry -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Yates, John T., Jr.
- Research, 1960-2015; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The series includes research done by John T. Yates, Jr. during his time at the National Bureau of Standards, the University of Pittsburgh, and the University of Virginia. Files may include his notes, annotated articles, drawings, and proposals. Topics include carbon nanotubes, atomic sources, carbon monoxide, desorption spectrometer, and the overarching topic of surface chemistry. Also included are journals containing notes on lectures that Yates attended spanning from 2000 to 2014 on subjects such as Astronomy, Scanning Tunnel Microscope, and general Surface Science.
  - Adsorbate Induced Surface Stress Abstract (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alkali and Ion Sources, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Astrochemistry (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
  - Astrochemistry General Information (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Atomic Hydrogen (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Atomic Force Articles (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Atomic Monoxide Sources, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Big Data, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Buckminsterfullerenes Adsorbate Displacement, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Catalysis Article, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Carbon Monoxide and Hydroxide, July 2014 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Carbon Monoxide Energy Distribution (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carbon Monoxide Insulators, November 1994 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Chemistry Related to Semi-Conductor, May 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Consideration of Absolute Qualities of Charge (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Consideration Notes, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Desorption Spectrometer (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Diamond Surfaces (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Dimensional Analysis of Diffusion, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Doe Proposal, August 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Drawings of University of Virginia Equiptment (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Electrochemistry by S. Doser, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Electron Stimulated Desorption, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Elementary Chemical Reaction (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Gas-Surface News Articles, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Gerhart Friedlander Autobiography (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Glass Ball Insulators, July 9, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Glycine and Amino Acid Surface Chemistry, 1981-1987 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Graphite Work, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - History of Surface Chemistry (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Ionizing Radiation Spectroscopic, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Irving Information (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Journey of a German Professor, 1905 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Lyman and Lester Andrews Notes, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Manuscript Work (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Metastables Surfaces with Martin and Metiu (Box 1, Folder 37-38)
  - Methanol Synthesis (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Microcalytic Reactor Drawings (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Mira Variables, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Mobility in Titanium Dioxide, October 2013 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Molecular Beam Doser Details, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Molecular Beam Drawings (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Molecular Dynamics Articles, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - The National Academies Keck Futures Initiative, November 2003 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Oral History Interview with John Hougen, November 2003 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Oral History Interview with John Yates Jr., January 23, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Organometallic Surface Chemistry (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Petel Molecular Electronics, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Photochemistry of Adsorbed Species (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Photochemical Surface Processes, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Pittsburgh Undergraduate Review, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Plasmonic Chemistry (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Polishing of Single Crystals, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Post-Doctoral Positions, July 1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Post-Surgery Thinking, 2015 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Predictions by Thomas, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - President Obama Address on Science and Innovation, April 27, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Pyroelectric Detectors, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pyrometry Tungsten Nomograph (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Research Accomplishments (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Research Problem Notes (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
  - Rotary Manipulator (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Scanning Tunnel Microscope at University of Virginia, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Scientific Collaborators, 1960-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Scientific Thoughts, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Shiliang Work, November 5, 2014 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Silvia Ceyer's Drawings (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Special Experimental Procedures (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Spectroscopy in Surface Science (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Summary of Electron Stimulated Desorption, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Surface Organometallic Chemistry Proposal (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Surface Photochemistry (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Thomas Jefferson, Astronomer, August 1943 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Transmission Infrared Cell, January 30, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Two Photon Photoemission as a Probe, December 14, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - United States Department of Energy Solar Industrial Program - Solar Detoxification Project, March 1998 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - University of Virginia Research, 2014-2015 (Box 2, Folder 33-34)
  - Work Methods, April 2014 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Work on Experiemental Innovations in Surface Science, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 100 Years of Quantum Mysteries, February 2001 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Lecture Journal, 2000-2011 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lecture Journal, 2004-2009 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lecture Journal, 2006-2008 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lecture Journal, 2006-2010 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Lecture Journal, 2010-2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Lecture Journal, 2011-2012 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Lecture Journal, 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Lecture Journal, 2011-2014 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Lecture Journal, 2012-2014 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Publications, 1984-2012; II.
  The series contains a sampling of the publication authored by John T. Yates, Jr. Included are magazine articles, reviews, book chapters, obituaries, and a publishing agreement
  - The Journal of Physical Chemistry, October 14, 2010 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Marine Chronometer Valuation Booklet, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notes on Molecular Physical Chemistry for Engineers Book, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Nuclear Research Facility Interface Research and Vacuum Physics Scientific Publications, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photochemistry on Titanium Dioxide, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Physics Today Madey Obituary, 2008-2009 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America Frontiers in Surface Chemistry, January 19, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Publishing Agreement, 2008-2011 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Articles for the Surface Science Center, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Review of "Introduction to Surface Chemistry and Catalysis", August 15, 2012 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Science Article Information, 1998-1999 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - The Search for the Active Site on Catalysis, July 2012 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Topics in CATALYSIS Magazine, May 2010 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Patent, 1982-2005; III.
  This series contains material pertaining to Yates' 2005 patent titled "Decontamination of Chemical Warfare Agents Using Reactive Sorbent." Included are graphs, correspondence, research, information about the patent process, and the patent.
  - Graphs and Diagrams for Patent, 1952-1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Patent Correspondence, 1982-1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Patent on Decontamination of Chemical Warfare Agents Using a Reactiver Sorbent, February 8, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Patent Process Information, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
  - Receipts, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Research Information, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- University of Pittsburgh, 1981-2006; IV.
  The series includes topics concerning Yates' time at the University of Pittsburgh. These files comprise his work on the Surface Science Center, interactions with the Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, floor plans for Alumni Hall, and correspondence between Yates and campus administrators, including Chancellor Wesley Posvar.
  - Alumni Hall Floor Plan (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cost of Moving from National Bureau of Standards to University of Pittsburgh, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Society for Analytical Chemists Pittsburgh Directory, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Appointment Correspondence, 1995-2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Facilities at Surface Science Center, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - History of the Surface Science Center, 1982-2005 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Information on Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Chancellor Posvar, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Moving Arrangments from University of Pittsburgh to University of Virginia, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Peterson Institute of Nanoscience Center, 2006 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Petrov Visit to Surface Science Center, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "To Do" List (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Photographs, Dr. Yates (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Scanning Tunnel Microscopy Lab at Surface Science Center, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Storage Infromation, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Surface Science Center Closing, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Surface Science Center Dedication, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Surface Science Center Inventory, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Surface Science Labs, 1981-2002 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Ultra-Violet Reactor Donation to Bulgarian Academy of Sciences, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - White Paper Proposal with Patek, 2004-2005 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Teaching and Lectures, 1980-2014; V.
  The series covers teaching material used by Yates in classes such as, Chemistry 1420, Chemistry 1480, Chemistry 3420, and Chemistry 3610. These materials include student readings, lecture slides, problem sets, schedules, notes, and syllabi. This series includes information on courses Yates taught at the University of Pittsburgh, University of Virginia, and various visiting appointments
  - Astrochemistry Lecture (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Bond Activation in Molecules Lecture (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Bunsen Convention, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Center for Chemistry of the Universe All Hands Workshop, Janurary 22, 2009 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Chapter 4: The Second Law Concept Notes (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Chapter 5: The Second Law Machinery Notes (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Chapter 6: Phase Transformation of Pure Substance Notes (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Chapter 9: Chemical Equilibrium Notes (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Chapter Summaries (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Chemical Reactivity at Surface Slides (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Chemistry 304 Notes (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Chemistry 1420 Handouts (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Chemistry 1420 Problem Sets (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Chemistry 1420 Schedule and Syllabus, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Chemistry 1480 Course Booklet (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Chemistry 1480 Exams and Answers, 2005-2006 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Chemistry 1480 Problem Sets, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Chemistry 1480 Syllabus and Schedule (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Chemistry 3420 Notes and Problem Sets, 2014 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chemistry 3610 Syllabus (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Debye Lecture (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
  - The Entry of Modern Surface Science Lecture (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Facile New Method for the Fluorination Lecture, October 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Heterogenesis Catalysis Slides (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Hercules and Roast Notes and Slides (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Humor Slides (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Iddles Lecture and Slides, October 1995 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Imaging Chemical Bonds Lecture (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Ioppolo Lectures, 2013 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Lecture Events, 1980-2001 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Lecture Images and Notes (Box 5, Folder 22-23)
  - Linear Gold Chains Slides, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Molecular Aspects Lecture (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - National Academy of Sciences Nanoscience Program, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - New Approaches to Aluminum Preservation Lecture (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - No Photodecomposition on Titanium Dioxide Slides and Lecture (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Novel Thin Film Production Lecture, January 9, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pendleton Lecture, June 27, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Phi Beta Kappa Lecture, June 19, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Photochemistry on Titanium Dioxide Surfaces Lecture (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Physical Issues in Surface Science Lecture (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Properties of Gases Slides (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Scanning Tunnel Microscope Images (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Surface Chemistry an Engine of Modern Technology Lecture (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Surface Kinetics Notes and Slides (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Synthesis of Biphenyl Notes and Slides (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Titanium Dioxide Lecture, October 29, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Tracking Motion of Molecules Lecture (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - University of Virginia Presentations, 2007-2009 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Experimental Innovations in Surface Science Textbook, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Molecular Physical Chemistry for Engineers Textbook, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Press, 1974-2006; VI.
  This series includes newspaper clippings, magazine articles, and published works on the career of John T. Yates, Jr. The articles are arranged according to his time at the National Bureau of Standards, the University of Pittsburgh, and the University of Virginia.
  - National Bureau of Standards Articles, 1974-1980 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - University of Pittsburgh Articles, 1982-2006 (Box 6, Folder 20-22)
  - University of Virginia Articles, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Correspondence, 1978-2014; VII.
  The series is a collection of letters and emails sent to and by John T. Yates, Jr. Included are correspondence with students, colleagues, and politicians, among others.
  - National Bureau of Standards, Employee Evaluation, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Congressional Luncheon, April 1, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence Regarding National Science Reports, 1996-2009 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Goodman Induction Letters, 2001-2002 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Juniata College, 2003-2006 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Student Correspondence [Restricted], 2001-2014 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Thank you Letters, 1990-1997 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - What's New with Bob Park Emails, 1996-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ziess-Buhl Email, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Events and Calendars, 1970-2014; VIII.
  The series includes information about events and professional travel during John T. Yates, Jr.'s career. Calendars, lectures and conference information, as well as notes regarding trips abroad, are present in this series.
  - Trip to England Summary, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Gordon Research Conference, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Guest Lectures Attended, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Scandinavia Trip, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Review Meeting for Research of Catalysis Research Center, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - National Research Council Workshop on Assessing the Value of Research in Chemical Sciences, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - New Zealand Trip, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Workshop on Graduate Education, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bulgarian Academy of Sciences Visit, 2005 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Calendar, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Calendar, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - International Symposium on Surface Science and Nanotechnology, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Calendar, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - NanoSTAR Spring Symposium, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - National Academy of Sceinces Symposium, 2009 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Calendar, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - John Yates Birthday Photos, August 3, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Calendar, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Berlin Trip, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Calendar, 2012 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Calendar, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Calendar, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Awards and Honors, 1973-2014; IX.
  The series includes correspondence, nominations, and programs regarding the various awards given to John T. Yates, Jr. over the course of his career. These awards span from local to international recognitions, including his appointment to the National Academy of Science, his visiting professorship to the California Institute of Technology, and the Langmuir award. The collection also includes nominations for awards Yates did not receive.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science Award, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - American Chemical Society, Chemical and Physics Award, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - American Chemical Society Fellowship, 2011 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Adamson Award (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Bower Award, 2004-2005 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Buck-Whitney Medal, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - California Institute of Technology Visiting Professor, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Centenary Lectureship, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Chemical Pioneer Award, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Debye Award, 2001-2007 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Department of Commerce Program, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - E.O. Lawrence Memorial, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Ertl Lecture Award, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Award Events, 1981-2006 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Humboldt Research Award for Senior U.S. Scientists, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Juniata College, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Kendall Award, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Langmuir Award, 2000-2005 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Madey Award, 2011 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Marley Award, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - National Academy of Sciences Award, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - National Academy of Sciences Information (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - National Bureau of Standards Award, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - National Science Board Award, 1984-1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Nevada Medal, 1999-2003 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Nicols Award, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Pittsburgh Award, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - President's Research Award, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Provost Award, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Thomas Jefferson Fellowship, 2007-2008 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Welch Award, 1989-2014 (Box 8, Folder 15-16)
  - Wesley Statton Award, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- 2021 Addition, X.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains presentations, course materials, and research pertaining to Yates' interests in chemistry and surface science. Also included are corresponence with colleagues and students, as well as information about awards and events held in his honor. Of note are photographs of events attended by Yates, trips abroad, and students he worked with at the University of Pittsburgh.
  - American Vacuum Society Certificate, October 1, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Annotations, 2002-2011 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Astrochemistry, 2009-2015 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Astrochemistry Lecture, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - AVS Awards Assembly and Reception Program, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Awards and Achievements, 1987-2013 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Cambridge Trip, April-November 2000 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - "Celebrating a Life in Surface Science: A Symposium in Honor of John T. Yates", 2016 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Chemistry Course Materials, 2007-2013 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence with Contemporaries and Colleagues, 1974-2000 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1992-2015 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence with Students, 2004-2013 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - David Wayne Goodman, 2009-2013 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - EUV-Induced Contamination Lecture (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Green Card and Visa Letters of Recommendation, 2007-2010 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Group Events, Invitations and RSVP Lists, 1999-2005 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Highly Cited Researchers Certificate, ISI Thomson Scientific (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Juniata 50th Class Reunion Book, May 2006 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Lab and Office Plans, 2006-2011 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Letters Nominating Colleagues and Students, 1999-2015 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Linnett Visiting Professorship, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Linnett Visting Professorship Lectures, 1999-2000 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Materials on Research and Teaching, 1991-2011 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Molecular Lectures, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina Alliance Lecture Program, April-June 2010 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Meetings, 2002-2009 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - NSF Funded Research on Molecular Electronic Behavior, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Personal and Family Materials, 2001-2018 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Personal Greeting Cards (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Rewrites and Revisions, 1999-2014 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Surface Science Center Booklet (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Science Magazines, 2004-2015 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Tohoku University Newsletter on the Surface Science Center, December 12, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Travel and Personal Life, 1982-2011 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - University of Delaware Seminar, February 15, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - University of Pittsburgh Surface Science Center, 1983-2005 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - University Publications, 2003-2008 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - University of Virginia Materials, 2009-2013 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - U.S Department of Commerce Honor Awards Programs, 1973, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Photographs - Friends and Family (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Photographs - Gordon Research Conferences, 1979-1999 (Box 9, Folder 22)